[
  {
    "question": "In 1946 Winston Churchill popularized what term used to describe Soviet relations with Western powers?",
    "answers": [
      "quagmire",
      "mutually assured destruction",
      "special relationship",
      "iron curtain"
    ],
    "correct": "iron curtain"
  },
  {
    "question": "Frequently cited as the counterpart to the CIA, what was the name of the Soviet intelligence agency?",
    "answers": [
      "SALT",
      "ICBM",
      "KGB",
      "DMZ"
    ],
    "correct": "KGB"
  },
  {
    "question": "An early move by the U.S. during the Cold War, the Marshall Plan had what goal?",
    "answers": [
      "to develop the hydrogen bomb",
      "to bring economic stability to postwar Europe",
      "to infiltrate Soviet intelligence agencies",
      "to flush communists out of US government"
    ],
    "correct": "to bring economic stability to postwar Europe"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which theory stated one country’s \"fall\" into communism would precipitate neighboring countries to do the same?",
    "answers": [
      "domino theory",
      "Chutes and Ladders theory",
      "hopscotch theory",
      "checkers theory"
    ],
    "correct": "domino theory"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a famous 1950s filmstrip shown in classrooms across America, Bert the Turtle offered kids what advice for surviving an atomic blast?",
    "answers": [
      "Dig a hole",
      "Climb a tree",
      "Run for your life",
      "Duck and cover"
    ],
    "correct": "Duck and cover"
  },
  {
    "question": "Often cited as their first regime change, the CIA deposed the prime minister of what country in 1953 after he nationalized their oil industry?",
    "answers": [
      "Iran",
      "Chile",
      "Nicaragua",
      "Congo"
    ],
    "correct": "Iran"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a failed attempt to overthrow communist ruler Fidel Castro, U.S.-funded Cuban exiles used which site to start their invasion?",
    "answers": [
      "Tiananmen Square",
      "Bay of Pigs",
      "Checkpoint Charlie",
      "Ho Chi Minh Trail"
    ],
    "correct": "Bay of Pigs"
  },
  {
    "question": "A direct \"hotline\" from the White House to the Kremlin was established as a result of which of these events?",
    "answers": [
      "Berlin blockade",
      "Gulf of Tonkin incident",
      "Cuban missile crisis",
      "kitchen debate"
    ],
    "correct": "Cuban missile crisis"
  },
  {
    "question": "Devised in 1959, the DEFCON system has five stages of military readiness. Which DEFCON rating is used when a nuclear attack is imminent or already underway?",
    "answers": [
      "DEFCON 5",
      "DEFCON 1"
    ],
    "correct": "DEFCON 1",
    "failure": 1.0
  },
  {
    "question": "American Francis Gary Powers gained notoriety during the Cold War because he...",
    "answers": [
      "fed sensitive documents to the Kremlin",
      "conducted \"witch hunt\" trials in Congress",
      "attempted to assassinate Ronald Reagan",
      "was captured while taking aerial photos of the USSR"
    ],
    "correct": "was captured while taking aerial photos of the USSR"
  },
  {
    "question": "Soviet Premier Nikita Khrushchev interrupted a United Nations meeting with which disruptive activity?",
    "answers": [
      "banging his shoe on a desk",
      "singing the Soviet national anthem",
      "eating a large, messy meal",
      "snoring loudly"
    ],
    "correct": "banging his shoe on a desk"
  },
  {
    "question": "True or false: The first woman in space was from the Soviet Union.",
    "answers": [
      "false",
      "true"
    ],
    "correct": "true"
  },
  {
    "question": "During one of the most famous Cold War speeches, who famously said the German phrase \"Ich bin ein Berliner?\"",
    "answers": [
      "Mikhail Gorbachev",
      "Ronald Reagan",
      "John F. Kennedy",
      "Josef Stalin"
    ],
    "correct": "John F. Kennedy"
  },
  {
    "question": "Although never fully leaving the organization, in 1966 what country withdrew its military from NATO and expelled NATO headquarters from its borders?",
    "answers": [
      "Poland",
      "West Germany",
      "United States",
      "France"
    ],
    "correct": "France"
  },
  {
    "question": "Often seen as the Soviet version of the United States’ Vietnam quagmire, the USSR’s 10-year-long invasion of what country began in 1979?",
    "answers": [
      "Poland",
      "Czechoslovakia",
      "Afghanistan",
      "Ukraine"
    ],
    "correct": "Afghanistan"
  },
  {
    "question": "Promising to defend against Soviet missiles using technology that had yet to be developed, Ronald Reagan’s 1983 Strategic Defense Initiative was often called by what nickname?",
    "answers": [
      "Star Wars",
      "The Matrix",
      "Back to the Future",
      "20,000 Leagues Under the Sea"
    ],
    "correct": "Star Wars"
  },
  {
    "question": "A Soviet policy instituted in the late 1980s, glasnost means what in English?",
    "answers": [
      "openness",
      "sacrifice",
      "submission",
      "punishment"
    ],
    "correct": "openness"
  }
]